Selection sort, selection sort is one algorithm used to sort a sequence of numbers.
Using a linear search, the smallest value in the sequence is located, a more detailed explanation
of linear search can be found later on in this course.
So this is a linear search.
We search through all the elements for the minimum.
We start by making the smallest value swaps with the left most number and is considered fully sold.
So the first step is indicating the minimum among all their values and we swept it to the left.
And we consider it as fully sorted.
The next step is if the smallest value happens to already be in the left most position, no operation
is get it out.
We start searching for the other elements for the eight other elements, and we found that two is the
minimum between them.
The same operations are repeated until all of the numbers are fully sorted.
We move to two there to that position after the one that we have fully sorted.
Now we have one and two fully sorted.
We search among the other seven elements, which is the main.
The minimum is three.
So we move three to the next of two.
Then we search for the other elements until detecting the minimum, which is four.
We move it to the left of the left most left and we search also the minimum, which is five five we
detected and we have in these elements, the minimum is six.
Then we move them.
We have three elements.
Seven is the minimum.
Then now we have eight and nine.
We search for the minimum between them, which is eight.
So we move it to the left and we still have one element and sorting is completed.
This is the selection sort.
This is how we search using how we saw an array using this election sort.
Now let's go in deep.
And this algorithm and see how the algorithm work, and let's implement it into coding and see language
and in Java like.